Guide to the Angier Biddle Duke papers, 1915-1990s and undated, bulk 1950-1995 RL.00326
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photograph Albums and Photographs Series, circa 1930s-1990s and undated
  - Album: Africa, undated (Box 50)
  - Album: Visit of Antonio Segni, President of Italian Republic to US Atlantic Fleet, Norfolk, Va., 1964, Jan. 16. (Box 50)
  - Album: President John F. Kennedy, circa 1961-1962 (Box 50)
  - Photographs: Various members of the Duke family, undated (Box 51)
    Loose photographs of Angier Biddle Duke, Robin Chandler (Tippett) Lynn Duke, and other family members.
  - Photographs: Biddle, Anthony Joseph Drexel, Jr. (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Bosch, Juan, President of Dominican Rep. (Box 52)
  - Darlington, Charles, and Chester Bowles and Lincoln Gordon (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Barnes, John; Roger W. Jones (Box 52)
  - Cabot, John M.; George W. Ball (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Juan Carlos, Prince, King of Spain; Sophia, Princess, Queen (Box 52)
  - Morales, Carrion; Adolphe Berle (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Carter, James Earl, Jr., and Rosalynn Carter (Box 52)
  - Grand Duchess Charlotte of Luxembourg (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Chiara, Robert F., President of Panama (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Unidentified Chinese artist (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Wymberley Coerv; Philip Coombs; Harlan Cleveland; William Crockett (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Crown Prince of Libya (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Anthony Drexel Biddle and family (Box 52)
  - Photographs: King of Afghanistan and party in Williamsburg on way to White House (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Aroesmenu, Carlos Julio, President of Ecuador (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Kennedy, John F., family members, and others (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Visit of Jacqueline Kennedy to Spain (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Pell, Claiborne; Angier Biddle Duke; John F. Kennedy (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Palomares Incident (Box 52)
  - Photographs: John F. Kennedy Sculptures (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Klaus, Josef, and others (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Kennedy, Jacqueline (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Angier Biddle Duke; Syrian government; Mrs. Charles A Lindbergh; Henry R. Labouisse; Bert Lance, et al. (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Archbishop Markarios at Cyprus (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Togo's Chief of Protocol, Douglas MacArthur II (Box 52)
  - Photographs: King of Burundi (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Oholensky, Serge; William Orrick; William Leonhart; Bowles; and Parsons (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Prosio, Manlio, Secretary General, NATO (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Dr. Platzer, Austrian Ambassador, presents medal to Mrs. Kennedy (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Haile Selassie (Box 52)
  - Photographs: C.B. Johnson (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Diem, President of South Vietnam (Box 52)
  - Hassan II, King of Morocco (Box 52)
  - Photographs: "Lady Bird" Johnson (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Abukhar, Balenk; John F. Kennedy; Angier Biddle Duke and family (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Fanfani, Prime Minister of Italy (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Johnson, Lyndon B., et al. (Box 52)
  - Photographs: "Duke Farm" (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Maria-Luisa de Aranha signing wedding registry after marriage to Angier B. Duke (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Duke, Anthony Drexel and family (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Duke, Angier Buchanan (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Estenssero, President of Bolivia (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Fray, Jacques, et al. (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Princess Grace of Monaco at Flamenco (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Ambassadors being sworn in (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Hussein, King of Jordan (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Roosevelt, Mrs. Franklin Delano, Ambassador A.B. Duke at swearing-in ceremonies (Box 52)
  - Photographs: Mwalimu, Julius K. Nyerere, Pres. of Republic of Tanganyika; John F. Kennedy (Box 52)
  - Photographs: San Martin, Juan Jose Espinosa (Box 52)
  - Album: Angier Biddle Duke and family, Jimmy Carter, et al. (Box 53)
  - Album: Radio Liberty Committee - Spain (scrapbook) (Box 53)
  - Album: Personal pictures, memorabilia, 1943-1944 (Box 54)
  - Album: Visit of the Secretary of Agriculture to Seville; Mrs. Orville (Jane) Freeman; Charles Nolan Consul General and wife; Douglas Crawford; Agricultural Attaché and wife (Box 55)
  - Photographs: Marilou Duke (Box 55)
  - Photographs: Official visit of Hon. Sir Abubakar Tafawa Balewa, Prime Minister Federation of Nigeria (Box 55)
  - Wedding scrapbook (names unknown) (Box 55)
  - Negatives (Box 56)
  - Album: Morocco (Box 56)
  - Album: Washington Duke memorial (Box 56)
  - Photographs: Wyndecote, 1987 (Box 56)
  - Photographs: Kennedy, Jacqueline (Box 56)
  - Photographs: Nyerere, President of Tanzania (Box 56)
  - Photographs: Johnson, Mr. and Mrs. Lyndon B. (Box 56)
  - Photographs: Erhardt, Ludwig (Box 56)
  - Photographs: Grand Duchess Charlotte of Luxembourg (Box 56)
  - Photographs: President of Panama, R. Chiara (Box 56)
  - Photographs: Kennedy, John F. (Box 56)
- Appointment Books Series, 1961-1991
  Bound personal appointment books and social calendars containing minimal entries with names, events, and times. Items occasionally laid in include business cards, brief messages, reminders.
  Series is in original order as received.
  - Appointment books, 1961-1991, 10 folders (Box 57)
- Subject Files Series, 1960s-1990s
  Created by Angier Biddle Duke, these files represent a broad range of subjects related to his professional activities from the early 1960s to the 1990s. Additional materials on the same subjects can also be found in the Miscellaneous Series.
  Materials are arranged in original order as received.
  - The Spanish Institute, Inc. (Box 58)
  - Foreign Policy Association (Box 58)
  - Moroccan-American Foundation (Box 58)
  - Sheila Isham (Box 58)
  - Resumes of Robin Chandler Duke and Angier Biddle Duke, 1990 (Box 58)
  - Long Island University (L.I.U.) Windmill Cartoon, 1988 (Box 58)
  - San Ten Karate Association Championship, Glenn Luyjet (Box 58)
  - L.I.U. Sag Harbor Initiative (Box 58)
  - Arthur Ross Foundation, 2 folders (Box 58)
  - L.I.U. - Rogers Memorial Library, 1987 (Box 58)
  - Horticultural Committee, Ellen Samuels, 1988 (Box 58)
  - Financial Tap, L.I.U. (Box 58)
  - I. U. Community Welcoming Reception, April 18, 1986 (Box 58)
  - Long Island University, 3 folders (Box 58)
  - L. I. U. Development, Major Donor Prospects, 1987 (Box 58)
  - L.I.U. Development, 1988 (Box 58)
  - Long Island University Chancellor's Award Gala Scholarships, 1986 (Box 58)
  - L.I.U. 60th Anniversary Convocation, November, 1986 (Box 58)
  - M.M. Anram, MD., Long Island College Hospital (Box 58)
  - Alumni Reunion, 1988 (Box 58)
  - 75th Birthday Celebration for A.B. Duke, 1990 (Box 58)
  - American Foundation for AIDS Research (Box 58)
  - Nicaragua (Box 58)
  - New Zealand (Box 58)
  - Prodemca (Box 58)
  - Council of American Ambassadors (Box 59)
  - Global Forum (Box 59)
  - For Our Children's Sake Federation (Box 59)
  - L.I.U. Trustees, WAF Council, WPBX Station (Box 59)
  - L.I.U. Planning Committee, Southampton Campus, Council of Overseas, Letters (Box 59)
  - Boys Harbor, Inc. (Box 59)
  - Hill and Knowlton Federation (Box 59)
  - Manaqua Conference-"Reflections on Transition" (Box 59)
  - Council of American Ambassadors, re: Cuba (Box 59)
  - U.S. Observer report to El Salvador elections (Box 59)
  - Panama, 2 folders (Box 59)
  - Panama speech treaties, 12/13 Letters to the Editor (Box 59)
  - Press Release (Nov. 28, 1977) (Box 59)
  - Panama Press Release (Box 59)
  - Democratic House and Senate Council (Box 59)
  - Asian/Pacific American Advisory Council (Box 59)
  - US International Council (Box 59)
  - Resumes (Box 59)
  - St. Paul's School (Box 59)
  - Coalition for a Democratic Majority (Box 59)
  - Duke University- Living History Program (Box 59)
  - Lists (Box 59)
  - Program for New World Anthropology (Box 59)
  - New York State Ethnic Advisory Council (Box 59)
  - Carey Campaign- Ethnic Advisory Council (Box 59)
  - Citizens T.F. Members (Box 59)
  - International Fund for Monuments (Box 59)
  - Council of American Ambassadors (Box 59)
  - Appeal of Conscience Foundation: Grant for Hungarian exchange (Box 59)
  - Adelphi Academy (Box 60)
  - "Ambassadors Abroad" (Box 60)
  - Council of American Ambassadors Metro. Club (Box 60)
  - Council of American Ambassadors (Box 60)
  - Council on Democratic Campaign for House and Senate (Box 60)
  - Dr. Diefenbach (Box 60)
  - Founder's Day- Presbyterian Church, 1986 (Box 60)
  - Duke University Jewish Center (Box 60)
  - Foreign Policy Association (Box 60)
  - Buster, Edward W.- Family Counseling Service (Box 60)
  - IRC Delegation to El Salvador Feb.-Mar. 1990 (Box 60)
  - Prodemca, 2 folders (Box 60)
  - Morocco (Box 60)
  - Jay Rutherfurd, 1987 (Box 60)
  - El Salvador Elections, Mar. 1989 (Box 60)
  - San Salvador, Letter to Editor- Dan's Papers, 1989 (Box 60)
  - Joy Silverman (Box 60)
  - Spanish Institute (Box 60)
  - US New Zealand Council (Box 60)
  - Jamestown Foundation (Box 60)
  - Conference on Northern Ireland (Box 60)
  - Armenian Heritage Project, Inc. (Box 60)
  - Global Conference of Spiritual and Parliamentary Leaders, Apr. 1988 (Box 60)
  - US-USSR Trade and Investment Institute (Box 60)
  - Humanitarian Foundation for Nicaragua (Box 60)
  - P.A. Wk. 1971 (Box 60)
  - Global Forum (Box 60)
  - Western Sahara Mission Report (Box 60)
  - International Rescue Committee (Box 60)
  - National Committee on American Foreign Policy (Box 60)
  - Prospectus- Cold War, Argentina and Spain (Box 60)
  - Freedom House (Box 60)
  - Who's Who (Box 60)
  - Beyond Apollo/Soyuz: Partnership for Progress (Box 60)
  - Institute for Central American Studies (Box 60)
  - Rutherfurd/Duke Audio-Visual Project (Box 60)
  - US Observer Delegation to El Salvador Elections (Box 60)
  - Israel Mission (Box 60)
  - Institute of East/West Business Dynamics (Box 60)
  - New York Dept. of Public Events (Box 60)
  - William C. Bullitt biography, 3 folders (Box 61)
  - Council of American Ambassadors, 2 folders (Box 61)
  - Freedom House (Box 61)
  - International Rescue Committee (Box 61)
  - NYC Dept. of Civic Affairs and Public Events, 2 folders (Box 61)
  - International Rescue Committee 1961-1971 (2 folders), 1972-1973, 1973 (2 folders) (Box 61)
  - Europe-America Conference, 3 folders (Box 61)
  - Democratic Party Abroad (Box 61)
  - Westminster Board of Trustees (Box 61)
  - Press releases, 2 folders (Box 62)
  - Fiscal Year Prospectus (1964), White House Executive Office Building, 3 folders (Box 62)
  - Papers on segregation, 2 folders (Box 62)
  - Papers on El Salvador, Nicaragua (Box 62)
  - U.S. observer delegation to El Salvador elections (Box 62)
  - U.S.-Japan Foundation, 3 folders (Box 62)
  - Morocco, 2 folders (Box 63)
  - Boys Harbor (Box 63)
  - DePeyster, Marilu (Box 63)
  - St. Paul's School (Box 63)
  - Appeal of Conscience Foundation (Box 63)
  - Eaton, William, 2 folders (Box 63)
  - Carter, Jimmy (Box 63)
  - Humphrey, Hubert (Box 63)
  - Cherne, Leo (Box 63)
  - New York City Democratic Committee (Box 63)
  - C.A.R.E., 2 folders (Box 63)
  - US-Japan Foundation, 4 folders (Box 63)
  - NY State Advisory Council on Ethnic Affairs (Box 64)
  - Ditchley Conference on Spain, NATO, and Western Europe (Box 64)
  - International Fund for Monuments (Box 64)
  - L.I.U. Southampton campus (Box 64)
  - Appeal of Conscience Foundation (Box 64)
  - Statue of Liberty- Ellis Island Foundation (Box 64)
  - Moroccan- American Foundation (Box 64)
  - Council of American Ambassadors (Box 64)
  - Spanish Institute (Box 64)
  - Panama Canal Trip (Box 64)
  - Nat. Committee on American Foreign Policy (Box 64)
  - Robin Chandler Duke (Box 64)
  - Middle East Trip (Box 64)
  - Winston Churchill Memorial- Westminster College (Box 64)
  - Palomares nuclear incident (Box 64)
  - Mission to El Salvador- A Freedom House Special Report (Box 64)
  - Democratic House and Senate Council (Mar. 6, 1979) (Box 64)
  - El Salvador Mission (1988) (Box 64)
  - Delegation to the Elections in El Salvador, 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Guyana Elections Project, 2 folders (Box 64)
- Audio, Film, and Video Series, 1965-1990s
  Audio reels and cassettes, filmstrips, and video cassettes concerning various major events in A.B. Duke's professional life. Also includes documentary videos, and ceremonies involving other persons.
  [Originals closed to use. A few use copies available and are noted under individual entries; otherwise, staff must arrange to have use copies made before materials can be accessed. Please consult with Research Services staff before coming to use this collection.]
  - OR1. President Lyndon B. Johnson's toast and Ambassador A.B. Duke's response (3/13/65) (audio tape) (Box 65)
  - OR2. Palomares (3/8/66) (audio tape) (Box 65, Digital-materials RL00326-SET-0001, Audio-file RL00326-RR-0002)
  - President Johnson's toast to Ambassador and Mrs. Duke (audio) (Box 65)
  - Angier Biddle Duke, US Ambassador to Madrid (4/18/67) (2 audio tapes) (Box 65)
  - Interview on Pakistani refugees (7/26/71) (audio) (Box 65)
  - Swearing-in: Ambassador Duke- Chief of Protocol (4/1/68) (audio) (Box 65)
  - Jack Valenti press conference (audio) (Box 65, Digital-materials RL00326-SET-0001, Audio-file RL00326-RR-0001)
  - Francis Plimpton Day (audio) (Box 65)
  - "Spain and Europe Today" (audio) (Box 65)
  - Film of ambassador's presentation of credentials (Box 65)
  - Global Forum (Box 65)
  - Global Forum II (Box 65)
  - Prof. Antonio Fontain TV Mon. Switzerland (2 audio tapes) (Box 65)
  - Fontain, Royal Privy Council (audio) (Box 65)
  - Gibraltar (10/26/67) (2 audio tapes) (Box 65)
  - "Celebrate New York" Program Series (10 tapes) (Box 65)
  - Presentation of Henry Morganthau Award to A.B. Duke by Henry Kissinger (Box 65)
  - Under Secretary of State- Economic Affairs Press Conference, Madrid 1966 (audio) (Box 65)
  - 1990 awards dinner (Box 65)
  - "Teenage Mothers: A Global Crisis" (Box 65)
  - People for Mrazek (Box 65)
  - "En Sus Propias Palabras"- Fidel Castro (Box 65)
  - "Morocco Video Showcase" (Box 65)
  - Mac Neil/Lehrer News Hour - Jan. 13, 1992 (Box 65)
  - "Decade of Decision" - Population Crisis Committee (Box 65)
  - "Science Held Hostage: RU486 and the Politics of Abortion" (unopened video) (Box 65)
  - "Profile in Excellence" (Box 65)
  - "Sustaining our Planetary Home" (Box 65)
  - Channel 2- "The People, Boys Harbor, Anthony Duke" (Box 65)
  - King Hussein's visit to the U.S. (film) (Box 65)
  - A.B. Duke before the National Democratic Club 6/2/66 (Box 65)
- Clippings Series, circa 1940s-1990s and undated
  Large series of clippings and press releases assembled by A.B. Duke. Subjects include major world events; marriages of A.B. Duke, close family and friends, including Jay Rutherfurd; events related to A.B. Duke's professional life; the nuclear incident at Palomares, Spain; and the death of his wife Maria-Luisa Duke in 1962. Several articles highlight Robin Chandler Duke's life. One folder of materials concerns Doris Duke's death and estate. The majority of the clippings are originals, but some deteriorated clippings have been photocopied.
  Arranged in rough chronological order.
  - (11 folders) (Box 66)
  - (17 folders) (Box 67)
- Printed Materials, circa 1950s-1990s and undated
  Books, pamphlets, periodicals, articles, minutes, reports of various kinds, printed speeches, leaflets, advertisements, business documents, fiscal analyses, programs, and various other materials. The books cover a wide range of topics: some are texts on foreign policy, diplomacy, and politics, while others (a few novels) seem to have belonged to the private reading libraries of Robin Chandler Duke and A.B. Duke. One book is a limited edition commemorating President Kennedy's inauguration. Other subjects cover JFK's assassination; Spanish business, trade, and foreign policy; Pakistani refugees; and Denmark. Many of the materials may relate to areas found under the Subject Files Series.
  - Printed materials: includes "Escape to Freedom: the Story of the International Rescue Committee" by Aaron Levenstein, 1983, 11 folders (Box 68)
    A.B. Duke played a major role in the efforts of IRC.
  - Printed materials, 11 folders (Box 69)
  - Printed materials: 9 books; various pamphlets (Box 70)
  - Printed materials, 13 folders (Box 71)
  - Four books (Box 72)
  - Printed materials; pamphlets, 5 folders (Box 73)
  - Foldered printed materials; four books, 4 folders (Box 74)
  - Printed materials, 12 folders (Box 75)
- Travel Series, 1965-1990 and undated (bulk 1965-1978)
  Routine travel schedules, itineraries, and other records for A.B. Duke and other people. Series is arranged in original order as received.
  - Travel records and related materials (Box 75)
- Other Papers Series, circa 1950s-1990s and undated (bulk 1970s-1990s)
  Series houses a range of materials generally not related to main series. Of significance are writings and speeches of authors other than A.B. Duke; subjects often include diplomacy and international politics. Includes large groups of invitations and guest lists as well as some memorabilia.
  - Travel files, 10 folders (Box 76)
  - Miscellaneous (one of these is a classified memo, American embassy in Manila), 5 folders (Box 76)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 17 folders (Box 77)
  - Invitations, guest lists, 14 folders (Box 78)
  - Various papers; Prodemca (1 binder); gold trinket, 5 folders (Box 79)
  - Various papers, 19 folders (Box 80)
  - Various papers and memorabilia, including JFK campaign button, 11 folders (Box 81)
- Oversize Materials, circa 1928-1969
  - Democratic Nicaragua advertisement (Box 82)
  - Esquire, 1963 Jan. (Box 82)
  - Pabst Blue Ribbon Beer advertisement featuring A. B. Duke and first wife (circa 1930) (Box 82)
  - Chopin, 2 record albums (Box 82)
  - 1964 Democratic National Convention Handbook (Box 82)
  - Diario de Colón, 2 copies (Box 82)
- Additional Oversize Materials
  - Clippings and printed materials (Box 88)
    Roughly 50 items on various subjects. Includes Spanish and Danish periodical clippings and newspaper clippings, including a commemorative publication for John Fitzgerald Kennedy, November, 1963, and a French fashion magazine, 1963. Other English-language items refer to the Kennedy family in Spain, and Lynda Johnson's trip to Spain. One lengthier article on radical feminists interviews Josephine Biddle Duke, student activist at Columbia University in 1969, and apparently a member of the Duke family.
- Accession (2000-0185), 1935-1992, 3 boxes
  Addition (1.2 lin. ft.) consists of documents relating to his time as Ambassador to El Salvador and Chief of Protocol.
  - Personal correspondence and notes, 1990s, 3 folders (Box Acc. 00/185 Box 1)
  - Official documents, photographs, and correspondence, 1935-1970s, 10 folders (Box Acc. 00/185 Box 2)
    These include documents and portraits of Duke and others, primarily from his time as ambassador in the 1960s. There are photographs (sometimes accompanied by person letters) of a number of heads of state, politicians, and others including Lyndon B. Johnson, Dean Rusk, Ronald Reagan, Grace Kelly, Chancellor Klaus of Austria, and other foreign dignitaries. Correspondents also include Gerald R. Ford. Documents include Duke's ambassadorship appointments from Johnson and Carter. There are also a few clippings, additional proclamations, and miscellaneous materials.
  - Appointment to Chief of Protocol from President John F. Kennedy (Box Acc. 00/185 Box 3)
  - Appointment to Ambassadorship in El Salvador from President Harry S. Truman (Box Acc. 00/185 Box 3)
  - Appointment to Chief of Protocol from President Lyndon B. Johnson (Box Acc. 00/185 Box 3)
  - Other nominations, appointments, resolutions, clippings, and a photograph with President Johnson, 2 folders (Box Acc. 00/185 Box 3)
  - Painted portrait of Duke, background set in Morocco (Box Acc. 00/185 Box 3)
- Accession (2009-0257), 1961-1980, 1 box
  Accession (2009-0257) (0.5 lin. ft.) consists of four For the Record books of speeches and other public remarks given by Duke during his time as Chief of Protocol (1961-1964) and as ambassador to Spain (1965-1967). Also includes a photo album souvenir of his official visit to the Allied Forces of Southern Europe in Naples in 1980.
  - Photo album: Visit to Allied Forces of Southern Europe, Naples, 1980 (Box (Acc. 09/257) 1)
  - For the Record volumes (Box (Acc. 09/257) 1)
    - Chief of Protocol, 1961-1964 (1 volume) (Box (Acc. 09/257) 1)
    - U.S. Ambassador to Spain, 1965-1967 (3 volumes) (Box (Acc. 09/257) 1)